Kyiv.Winter that changed us.
You are my child, you understand? You have to give
me grandchildren, and you are going under the bullets.
"I love Ukraine". They kill
our children, and you say I love Ukraine.
What kind of love for Ukraine is this? Bendery
Children have to be protected.
Send them not to the first barricade, but to third.
Self-defence.
They take away our rights!
They don't give us our rights!
You have to understand
that you take responsibility.
You have to understand that you take
responsibility for your house and everything here.
Because if you tell them that something is
gone, it will be a personal problem for you.
I know what I'm doing.
The fourth is left at the entrance.
Two inside, two outside, near the doors.
Be careful not to break
anything, don't break anything.
Self-Defense Forces takes it under its protection
the abandoned building of the Ministry of Culture
so that it doesn't lose its
property and documents.
The man giving out the orders is nicknamed Dobry.
In his everyday life, he is a Kyiv entrepreneur,
who is on the Maidan from the first days.
I have a five-year-old son.
And so that I don't feel
ashamed in front of him,
when he grows up, he will ask,
Dad, what did you do at that time,
when such people ruled our country?
How did you feel? What did you do?
I will tell him that I was engaged in business,
earned money, I realized that I would be ashamed.
I will lie, I will be hypocritical,
and I don't want to live like that.
Demonstrators in construction helmets,
ready to defend the peaceful protest,
appeared after the students
were beaten on the Maidan.
I came voluntarily.
My heart ached for all
the guys after the 30th.
Quiet!
Knees!
Why?
I'm falling!
People realized that they had to
defend themselves from the police.
If suddenly we succeed, God
willing, we succeed today to rest,
we, in any case, who rests, who
acts, we will be here tomorrow at 10 am.
Attention!
Key points!
We are the defense of the peaceful protest.
Our key task is not to allow the beating
of women and children.
We do not do any aggressive actions.
We only protect the people who
came to the peaceful protest of Kyiv.
After the first public meeting
and clashes with the police
under the administration of the President,
the demonstrators began to build
barricades on the Maidan of Independence.
The central square of the capital
began to resemble the real Sich.
People gathered where
there was a threat of assault.
And it was they who organized
the first self-defense camps.
You have a shield!
You are not there to drive flies away!
Fix the shield!
Protect as much as possible!
You are high, you can move,
but you will not be pushed!
This is the most stable
position of a person!
Khan is a former military man.
After the first attempt
to storm the Maidan,
he began to teach people how to withstand
the attacks of the security forces.
It became clear that in order to withstand
the pressure, the camps must be organized.
In that way self-defense has
become a full-fledged structure
that consisted of hundreds, as it
used to be in the Zaporizhzhya Sich.
The most protected people are young people.
No women, no kids.
This defense on this barricade
is completely self-organized.
Without the support of
any party, it is apolitical.
Now the countermeasures have begun!
One, two, three!
We are just restraining them, we have no goal
or task to attack the special police unit.
We are only defending ourselves.
People who simply pass
and change from time to time.
Here we just united.
The most wrong thing that the current
government has done is to anger people,
and the second thing is that
it gathered us in one place.
It was a point of resistance.
This is the point, people understood
that it needs to be strengthened.
We came here every evening, after a
day or two days, and we were on duty.
We were divided into dozens.
We said, guys, you have 12 or 15 people, determine
which of you is the most experienced soldier,
or has some military
experience in managing people.
And then there was a tenner.
There were moments when during the duty,
at night, the guys re-elected a tenner
if suddenly they didn't like something.
It's all about democracy
in its purest form.
Leave the place immediately!
Every day, self-defense caught provocateurs or pickpockets,
which were appeared at the perimeters of Maidan.
After the interrogation, sometimes
with clubs, they were released.
Take his hand!
I calmly give you everything.
Where`s a knife?
This morning, the fighters
arrested a man who was trying
to cut off the flags of
Ukraine around the tent town.
Khan at his barricade also fought with
the flags too, although the party ones.
There isn't, wasn't, and won't
be a single flag on this barricade.
I'm giving it to you personally.
And I wanted to tell you-
I'm giving the flags to the party representatives.
But if I see any other party
flags, I won't give it to them.
I'm going to destroy them.
I asked you not to hang them.
There are flags in Ukraine, European Union.
And there are Ukrainian nationalists, that's all.
Again, this is the difference between
the Soviet and non-Soviet approach.
The Soviet approach is that it's not all mine,
but I'm at the uncle's service, whose it is.
Or in the party.
Or in someone else's.
And self-defense and the
civil society and, let's say,
the essence of the Maidan,
in fact, are still people.
These are nations that we
believe that we are on our own land.
The rules of behavior on this land and the
laws that do not work and all this horror.
This is not normal for life.
I'm going to the Maidan,
so I'm going home again.
Self-defense was patrolled
every night, several times.
To track how the police forces move around the
Maidan and be ready for a possible assault.
Behind them is Berkut.
I'll take the 6th.
We are now turning around and running.
No, we don't have to
run, we just go quietly.
Let's go.
I'll be back.
I have nothing against you.
I am sure you have nothing against me
too, because we don't even know each other.
We don't even know each other.
Just think before doing anything.
Before going forward, and you will go forward,
before doing something, think for a second.
What are you doing? Really.
Today, tomorrow will pass, the orders will also
pass, tomorrow will come, the day after tomorrow.
What will happen next?
Our band, which will be.
And then take with you the same
brethren, with the same hand.
And sign up for self-defense today.
We don't let such people.
I want to show you.
I worked in Donbass
for 10 years as a soldier.
I was detaining Sokol.
Either from Lviv or Donetsk, it doesn't
matter to us, we have nothing to do with it.
We only let people in when they are sober.
What language do you speak?
I like everything, language.
There is no difference for me.
Everyone speaks in the language they know.
What about Ukrainian?
Ukrainian, Russian, same thing to us.
We don't have anything that we
ban Russian language.
I speak Ukrainian!
Alright.
Let`s go.
Sorry.
At 6, when the subway opened, a lot
of drunkards came crawling from there.
In the morning there is always
as we call it a "drunk storm".
People were constantly
passing.
We send them to the Teatralna station so
that they don't even come close to Maidan.
Attention! Attention! Hold it!
Today we are going to
the barricade at Yanukovych's cortege in Mezhyhirya.
We will picket a possible cortege
exit from two exits in Mezhyhirya.
For people who live nearby
and suffer from the noise you create,
we remind you that the law provides for administrative liability
for violation of silence between 22:00 and 8:00.
Stop the noise! Respect the rights of others!
I, at my 72 years old, paid the last 50 hryvnias
for a taxi to come here and support my people.
And what are you doing? You
have black suits and black souls.
The 11th played a very important role in the fact
our enemies saw how quickly Maidan could expand.
What they see, through the optics, through the
cameras, through the observers, through the knockers.
They know, there are
3,000 or 5,000 people here.
But then, hop, two hours pass,
and there are 15,000 people here.
And after two hours, there
are already 50,000 people here.
And in the morning, almost
a million people come.
It was simply cynical to sit at home, knowing that the
story has come, and to be a spectator of this process.
Because they say, well, guys, come on, come
on, we are worried about you on Maidan.
And to be safe, in warmth, in comfort.
Therefore, I realized that for me it was
hypocrisy, and I went there, to be a participant.
I think the logic is this. They said, we are
building a barricade on Olgirskaya Street.
This is the street that goes down.
These people began, as I understand it,
to guard until they build this barricade.
From whom?
But if suddenly, these
people will come here.
From where? From there?
From there, from the Bankova.
From Bankova? They won't leave.
No, well, I know.
Well, why did they put it?
Well, this is my opinion.
I say, if they have nothing
to do, let them build it.
Well, what an idiot to build a barricade close,
roughly speaking, to the enemy territory.
We just always waited for them to shoot,
just to put a machine gun on the building
and some night they will just start shooting the
Maidan from some high building, like this, straight.
Well, it almost turned out that
way, but they shot from Institutska.
Here, and with snipers.
And so, of course, from the point of view of
defense, all this, how to say, it was conditional.
It was with the condition that
they would not shoot at us.
There is a concept of honor and dignity of the
officer, yes, there is a oath, something else.
And the code of honor.
The rules of war, the laws
of war imply that an attack on a
building and a car marked with a red
cross or a red crescent is prohibited.
Right?
It is forbidden to shoot
non-combatants, that is, people
who are not regular
fighters of regular units, right?
Well, roughly speaking,
there was a mass protest here.
Yes, there is acceleration according
to the instructions, but women.
That is, did they pose
a threat to them? No.
Did the doctors pose a threat? No.
Why are they shooting at them?
I will never understand this,
and we will never forgive this.
There is such a man from Kharkiv,
Hobkin or Dobkin, the one who
promised that he would dress
as a Berkut, that he was so healthy.
Uncle Vanya calls him to a duel.
He wants to fight with him.
So that he is not a thug.
Two months after the first day of the
protests, despite the fights and arrests of
activists, there was a limit that neither
the police nor self-defense could cross.
Human life.
Everything changed after the first death.
And the resistance turned into a real war.
We don't throw stones yet.
And we are trying to push those
who will throw until my command.
To those who see me.
If something happens to me,
just know that I`m.
Glory to Ukraine!
Freedom to Ukraine!
People are a terrible
force if they are angry.
But while we were holding
back, no one was angry.
No one didn't shoot, we didn't kill them.
Although we could have
killed them in different ways.
If we take anger, when you
don't think about anything,
then of course we would
have killed them very quickly.
Only we would have looked
much worse for the whole world.
And we understood that too.
Therefore, to say that we were
unarmed, someone used the weapon,
someone brought it with him to the
Maidan, someone was ready to shoot,
and someone was shooting, there are
many dead people from the other side too.
But it wasn't the general idea.
One for all and all for one!
And there was another meeting.
With whom do you think?
With the front one.
You must have been tense.
I`m tense.
Not all of those present are aware of some
of the family peculiarities.
But we'll keep quiet about that. So, ...
They sent us a carrier pigeon.
Is this the one that
burned while flying over the barricades?
Cheers, men, to your health.
Be strong!
In a month, during the self-defense shooting
at Instytutskyi, Khan will be badly wounded.
He will receive a few sniper bullets.
His life will be saved by doctors.
At the end of the confrontation, the
self-defense forces will count 12,000 people.
Almost 100 of them will die.
Winter that changed us.