[male]: Yes, a nurse is needed, carefully.
[male]: But you have no work experience.
[female]: But I have a diploma.
[male]: Careful.
[male]: This is a centrifuge.
[male]: God bless you.
[female]: Good afternoon.
[male]: What did you say?
[female]: I told I have a diploma.
[male]: A diploma is good.
[male]: What is this?
[male]: So they brought him here?
[male]: No, it was in the box.
[male]: It just didn't fit in the box.
[male]: This is an ultrasound.
[male]: It's super complicated.
[male]: It costs twenty thousand euros.
[male]: Do you understand?
[male]: That's not possible!
[male]: Chief, everything is fine.
[male]: This isn't the first medical thing that cost 20,000 I've driven.
[male]: Really?
[male]: Ok, first time.
[male]: So where is it?
[male]: To the left.
[male]: And carefully.
[male]: Come on.
[male]: Excuse me, but why did you work as a journalist, a blogger?
[male]: Did you even do cinema?
[female]: A very dubious story.
[female]: Maybe later I'll tell you.
[male]: Julia.
[male]: Nursing is, first of all, experience, practice.
[male]: I need a qualified general nurse.
[female]: Yes, I…
[male]: Not for taking pots.
[female]: Wait, I can not just taking pots.
[female]: I remember very well where to stick needles in people.
[male]: Where are you from?
[male]: From Warsaw.
[male]: I did my internship there.
[male]: Then Krakow.
[male]: What is this?
[male]: Doctor!
[male]: Doctor, Kobita is here...
[male]: What is he saying?
[male]: I understood two words at most.
[male]: I understood four, Kobita, some woman killed someone or something.
[male]: What happened?
[male]: I say Kobita...
[male]: It`s about fruit, I know, but what's the point here?
[male]: And he says he brought a woman who had a car accident on the road.
[male]: Well?
[male]: So what can we do?
[male]: The hospital is closed.
[male]: Yes, show me.
[male]: There are no hospitals nearby, only the county hospital is 70 kilometers away.
[male]: Show me.
[male]: Guys, on three!
[male]: One, two!
[male]: Yes!
[female]: Hey, it's Margarita Romanovna!
[male]: Go-go-go!
[male]: To the observation deck!
[male]: Hospital.
[male]: Margarita Romanovna?
[female]: This man bring me to visit a Jew.
[female]: Do something, or I'll die and it'll be worse for you.
[male]: Why are you here?
[female]: Because we need to make anticonvulsant and analgesic.
[female]: Can I?
[male]: In the box.
[male]: Yes, Mark, Jeremy, there is an ultrasound machine in the operating room.
[male]: Try running it.
[male]: Okay.
[male]: Good afternoon.
[male]: I see, I come very timely.
[female]: What are you doing here, Kovaliov?
[male]: Surprise.
[female]: Not successful.
[female]: Are you serious?
[male]: Mind your own business.
[male]: What do we have here?
[male]: Traumatic brain injury?
[male]: One hundred for forty.
[male]: Hortostatic hypotension.
[male]: Adrenaline.
[male]: Find adrenaline.
[female]: Okay.
[male]: Who are you?
[male]: I'm Andriy, a surgeon.
[male]: And that`s my CV.
[male]: Above the skull, please.
[male]: Skull is normal.
[male]: Let`s look at stomach.
[male]: The stomach needs immediate surgery.
[male]: How to operate?
[male]: Our operating room is not ready.
[male]: The electricity is unstable.
[male]: We don't have an expert opinion.
[male]: But here`s the first patient, I welcome you.
[male]: To the operation room.
[male]: Let's go.
[female]: I have adrenaline.
[male]: Listen, this evacuation is making me nervous.
[male]: I have patients in Odessa, you can see the sea, but what about here?
[male]: The painful back and also there is smell of gasoline.
[female]: Dad, I'm beg you to get off your back.
[female]: I need you with Semen, Semen, don't get in the backpack, to take you out from under the shelling that's getting on my nerves.
[female]: So I'll take you out.
[female]: And you sit there, silently missing Odessa.
[female]: Because I'm driving.
[female]: I don't have time for your nostalgia.
[male]: Oh, it's hard to breathe.
[male]: Look, there's a hospital.
[female]: Father, what is it?
[male]: Baby, you should probably drop me off, and I'll get better and catch up with you in Poland.
[male]: As healthy as a doorman in a metropolis.
[female]: Okay.
[female]: We're turning.
[male]: And yes.
[male]: So what?
[male]: Let's see what fabrics.
[male]: Yes, liver and pancreas are intact.
[male]: Intestines too, I think.
[male]: I think so.
[male]: You said you were a surgeon.
[male]: What experience do you have?
[male]: What specialization?
[female]: An outstanding gynecologist.
[female]: And a talented schemer.
[female]: Specializes in women, mostly beautiful ones.
[female]: Simply put, a rare fool.
[female]: I haven't forgotten anything, Kovalev.
[male]: Sorry, but this is not your profile.
[male]: A person has everything close together inside.
[male]: Take a look.
[male]: This is a piece of metal.
[male]: It needs to be removed, treated, and sewn up.
[male]: I can handle this.
[male]: You will assist.
[male]: Let's go.
[female]: Come on.
[male]: Thank you.
[male]: Panel...
[male]: Tighten it here, tighten it there and it should work.
[male]: Why aren't you working?
[male]: Are you a plastic surgeon?
[male]: Yes, Jeremy Malifano, MD from Miami.
[male]: You speak strangely as for a dude from Miami.
[male]: Yes, my mother is from here in Poltava and her parents are too.
[male]: Why isn't this pile of junk metal working?
[male]: Can we increase the pressure or add lubricant?
[male]: Oh, you're an anesthesiologist?
[male]: Yes, Nazar from Ternopil.
[male]: Yes, guys, go away.
[male]: Are you an osteopath or a traumatologist?
[male]: I am Polish.
[male]: It's clear that the light will go out.
[male]: I'm after the details, because it's only enough for an hour at most.
[male]: What did he say?
[male]: That he's our fairy godmother.
[male]: Where is your doctor?
[male]: I don't know.
[female]: He don`t know.
[female]: Doctor!
[female]: Doctor, can you come here?
[male]: What happened?
[female]: My father feel so bad.
[male]: What's wrong with you?
[male]: My heart is hurting.
[male]: It's hard to breathe.
[male]: It`s burning here.
[male]: Yes, okay.
[male]: Come here.
[male]: Sit down.
[male]: Merik!
[male]: Merik, we have a patient.
[male]: Suspected heart attack, be careful.
[female]: Father, please don't die, I beg you.
[male]: Mom, I feel bad too.
[female]: Sioma!
[female]: What are you?
[male]: What about you?
[male]: I feel nauseous and my stomach hurts.
[female]: I told you not to eat that hot dog at the gas station.
[male]: Mom, calm down.
[male]: Now we'll do some tests and find out everything.
[male]: Mom.
[male]: Where he`s so long?
[male]: It's already an hour.
[male]: Marco!
[male]: Yes, take the boy.
[male]: Let's go, carefully.
[female]: A complete violation of security rules.
[female]: I don't even have a belt.
[female]: And you too, by the way.
[male]: And there's nowhere for the belt to put on.
[male]: And in general, when there's a war, such little things don't matter.
[female]: When there is war, everything matters.
[male]: But there is something more important, I'm taking it now.
[female]: Oh, we passed the speed limit sign, by the way.
[female]: You have much more on your speedometer.
[male]: Don't look there, look ahead.
[female]: God forbid it shakes and I have to clean the car afterwards.
[male]: I am, dear, now being chased by the weight of death.
[female]: Yes, I see.
[female]: Are you in a hurry to the cemetery?
[male]: I'm rushing to the hospital where a person is dying.
[male]: Because in the hospital there is a complete mess and there is no electricity.
[male]: And you, young lady, are carrying salvation in your arms for the head of the same TG.
[male]: So please hold it more gently.
[male]: What are you doing! Idiot!
[female]: Please, at least follow the vocabulary!
[female]: Good afternoon.
[female]: Hello, girls.
[female]: I'm Shura.
[female]: Galya.
[female]: Julia.
[female]: New nurse.
[female]: And that guy who watched our Margarita with you, is he your husband?
[female]: Galya.
[female]: That's how they look on men.
[female]: And she looked at him like that.
[female]: This is her ex.
[female]: This is the level of analytics, that's what I understand.
[female]: Can you analyse in the same way when the war is over?
[female]: We don't think about war at all.
[female]: Can we not think about it?
[female]: If you think about it, you might get a heart attack.
[female]: And then who will clean, disinfect, and cook here?
[female]: By the way, do you know how to cook?
[female]: I can.
[male]: If she knew how to cook, men would be attracted to her.
[female]: And you'll remember scrambled eggs until you retire, right?
[female]: Oh, that man doesn't know how to fry eggs yet, he's not a man at all.
[male]: What?
[female]: I'm saying we've already disinfected the operating room.
[female]: You go and work.
[female]: Doctor.
[female]: Girls, shall we work together?
[female]: Done.
[female]: Cool, right?
[male]: Hello.
[male]: The generator is about to die.
[male]: Serhiy went to get spare parts.
[male]: Galya asked to bring some toilet duck.
[male]: I said, the animal shouldn`t be in the hospital.
[male]: It's detergent.
[male]: Will we have some kind of a manager?
[male]: It won`t be.
[male]: But I can make you.
[male]: Do you want it?
[male]: I am a doctor.
[female]: Good afternoon.
[female]: I was told that the hospital is open here.
[male]: No, we open tomorrow.
[female]: Then excuse me, I'll go.
[male]: Wait.
[male]: The doctor will examine you.
[male]: Malifan, take the patient.
[male]: Sorry, I can't.
[male]: Why?
[male]: You are not busy right now.
[male]: So get ready and come take a look.
[male]: I'll show you around.
[male]: But how?
[male]: I am alone.
[male]: I need some kind of nurse.
[female]: Are you trying to control me?
[male]: I want to make sure you don't screw up.
[male]: Mosquito.
[female]: I'm not screwing up.
[male]: I'm not sure, cat, because it's not a mosquito, but a bilort clamp.
[female]: That's why I won't tolerate you again.
[male]: As a gynecologist, I advise you not to tolerate, but to do your job.
[male]: And, if you can, relax and enjoy yourself.
[male]: Colleagues, I need help examining a patient.
[male]: She's so aggressive that she has to be held?
[male]: I don't understand what you mean?
[female]: He asks why you can't examine it yourself?
[male]: Because it's protocol.
[male]: I can't examine a woman without a witness.
[male]: There is no such protocol in Ukraine, so go and do what you have to.
[male]: And God is your witness.
[male]: God's testimony is not admissible in court.
[male]: Tongs.
[male]: Well, so what?
[male]: Well, that's it.
[male]: Now we'll sew up the patient and you can take Yulia away forever.
[male]: Just my personal advice – don't marry her.
[male]: Okay, I'll wait.
[female]: Needle, please, and sew up your black man's mouth.
[male]: Kitty, kitty, you used to like it.
[female]: No, no, no.
[female]: When was that?
[male]: Generator went out.
[male]: Hurry up, drainage and tampon.
[female]: It seems our patient did not allow the hospital to be connected to the village network.
[male]: Nothing, we won't let this karma come true.
[male]: Come on.
[female]: Thank you.
[female]: So, how are my men?
[male]: Everything will be fine, don't be nervous.
[male]: Now we'll just measure the temperature and pressure.
[male]: Mom, I don't have any pain anymore.
[male]:  I think I'm feeling a bit sick.
[female]: Well, yes.
[male]: The temperature is good.
[male]: Oh, my heart is pounding.
[male]: Mr. Josef, now.
[male]: One second.
[male]: I want to draw.
[male]: It's good that the heart monitor is battery-operated.
[male]: Wow!
[male]: You have pressure like an astronaut.
[female]: What are you saying?
[female]: Dad, what was that?
[female]: Well, what are you doing, like a potato in a frying pan?
[female]: I understand that you don't want to go.
[female]: But to manipulate the fact that I'm worried about you.
[male]: My heart ached with longing for my native Odessa.
[male]: Baby, what will I do in that Poland?
[male]: There I`m a respectable person here.
[male]: Joseph L. Pinfelfein.
[male]: Who's there?
[male]: An old Jew?
[male]: Yosya is a pensioner.
[female]: Dad, it's because I'm worried about you and I'm taking you away from this damn war.
[female]: So now I'm going to go, buy some water, nausea lozenges and we're leaving, okay?
[male]: Grandpa, I was painting a bad cardiogram for you.
[male]: And bad tests.
[male]: You are my little sunshine.
[male]: You're my darling.
[male]: I don't want to go either.
[male]: But you can't lie.
[male]: No, you can't.
[male]: No, Siomochka, mom is doing the right thing by taking you away from here.
[male]: And me as the old man is better off here.
[male]: This is my land.
[male]: My life.
[male]: – And mine too.