Ukraine. Dniester. 2017
Holy Mother of Heroes.
Come to my heart.
Caucasian winds blow in a storm.
Friends, today you will watch an episode that will be different
from all those episodes that were on my channel before.
Because today we are going by an invitation to visit Azov.
And now we are 20 kilometers
away from their combat positions.
We are going by invitation to good friends,
Ilya Samoilenko and Bogdan Krotevych.
Because there is a special occasion.
Ten years since the founding of Azov.
There is a special occasion and there is a tremor, of course.
Apparently, it was a hall.
Because there were obviously places to sit.
A part from the Journey of Onegin.
I lived in Odesa then.
Dusty.
Stay here, Alexander Sergeyevich Pushkin.
Russians are scum.
Implementation of the Cold War Plan by the USSR...
Please tell us about blood transfusion because
it is talked about as know-how, but it had been prohibited before.
It had been prohibited. There wasn't enough determination.
Will is needed everywhere, right?
Grandmothers and grandfathers are sitting there on the benches.
You pass by, they look at you like this and think,
A fascist?
Really?
Yeah.
Why do you constantly troll
Spartan about age?
No, I'm Spartan, he's Iraq.
Sorry, Iraq.
Because I ...
Because he loves me.
I'm younger.
34.
I'm not younger, but I'm older.
But I'm older and wiser, right?
Yes.
So he doesn't relax.
I understand, but not really.
I will still go with it and I will think about your words.
Redis, tell me, what kind of person is he?
A standard.
What is the distance between you and him?
So how will this war end?
Moseychuk + Azov. Episode 1.
'Irak' and 'Spartan'.
Well, friends, we are in the Serbirian
forestry, our group came here quite early.
We will stay here until the evening
because we want to see the medical evacuation,
and how it is arranged in the Azov brigade.
Of course, the location itself, this is
the location of the brigade, is impressive,
because the forest has burned out, a
little further, where the guys are fighting,
it is practically gone.
When I compared and googled the Serbirian forestry,
it showed, you know, such a rich,
very dense, beautiful forest.
And now I see tree trunks.
Well, unfortunately, you can't turn the
camera there, where this picture is,
but this is what this forest looks like now,
where the fighting is.
Well, that's where we'll go in the evening.
Explosions are raging here, and we hear them.
I can't say that it's very scary,
maybe this wave of courage is
radiating from our Azov soldiers who are here.
All these guys are saying, they
are tired after the combat missions,
they are sleepless.
But they agreed to these talks, they came to these interviews.
A huge thank you to them for this.
But all these words that you hear from
them, you know, they are so significant,
they are so true, and they are very honest.
We talked about different things, we talked about
life, military life, and survival in general, as they say.
About the military ethics, about the needs of the Azov regiment,
about how the Armed Forces of Ukraine should be reconstructed,
about vertical and horizontal management and subordination.
In a word, good conversations with the right people.
Once again?
If you have seen these conversations,
then you know what it means.
Yes.
It means the beginning.
Natalia.
Spartan.
Iraq.
Why Iraq?
I, perhaps, will firstly answer this question.
Before that, I already had the practice of small interviews.
I have always responded that I do not discuss this topic.
It is personal for me.
Well, I'll put it this way.
In short, Iraq because it is a power, a strength,
it is a constant thirst for self-reliance,
and it is a country of the male race.
That's all about this topic.
When did you come up with such a pseudo?
Well, it was before Azov.
It was before Azov.
And in Azov, let's say, I have already put it to work.
I see.
Spartan, is it from a character or from a fighting vehicle?
No, I have a tattoo.
I did it in 2019.
And when I was at BITC, I went out in the morning from the
bathroom without a T-shirt, without anything, only pants.
Our instructor saw me, saw the tattoo, and he called me that.
Well, he said without a second thought.
Spartan. That's all.
Yes.
Why are you insecure about your Ukrainian?
You have good Ukrainian.
Yes.
Well, I've got into character already.
We are trying.
Where are you from?
Dnipro.
From Dnipro.
And you?
I'm from the Donetsk region.
Donetsk region.
Is this part occupied now?
No, thank God, not yet.
Well, I hope it won't be.
Well, we will put in as much effort
as possible so that it does not happen.
When did you come to Azov?
In 2022.
At the end, somewhere.
In October.
We came together.
In October at the same time.
Did you know each other before that?
Yes.
Were you friends before that?
Where did you meet?
We ...
In the police.
Did you both serve?
Yes, we served in one unit.
This is a special police unit, which, well,
has the function of performing force support
of the police,
ensuring force support of public mass events, security of the public order,
and support in the conduct of investigations.
Well, in general, force support.
Well, did you work in Dnipro?
Yes.
Both of you in Dnipro?
How did the decision to go to Azov emerge?
Why Azov?
I have my own reasons, let Spartan talk.
When it was in March, at the beginning of
March, we had such great excitement.
And when there was already an understanding that Mariupol
was already surrounded, and the guys needed help.
At that time, there were also police units, and this issue
of the unblocking came up, and we tried to get there.
We came to our management and asked, they said no, you can't.
We began to look for other corridors to get
there and even considered leaving the job.
We wanted to leave if we were not allowed to leave by
transfer, although Azov belongs to the National Guard,
the National Guard belongs to the MIA.
We were also in the ranks of the MIA.
I didn't understand why.
We really wanted to help.
Did you have friends there?
I personally had two of... well,
I can't say that they're my friends.
These guys were from my city, I knew them personally.
One of them is still in captivity, unfortunately.
One of them returned during the first exchange.
Just the understanding that the guys needed help,
and at that moment they were in a very difficult state.
I just wanted to help, I wanted to do something, because at that
moment we were in Dnipro, and there were no active hostilities there.
There were shelling, there were saboteurs and so on.
I really wanted to help with something.
Plus, you know, it also affected me that
everything was going on in my motherland.
And I couldn't help right now.
Then, we decided.
It was just problematic to get there.
To join there.
When it was September,
we saw that there was the first recruitment
after Azovstal for the BITC in Azov.
And that's it.
We submitted the application right away.
We went to the interview.
Then we took a vacation
and went to the BITC.
Still being policemen, we went
on vacation in order to qualify in Azov.
Yes.
Then, after the vacation...
With whom did you talk in Azov?
Did Krotevych select?
No.
Well, before that, there were two attempts for us to
join the then Special Operations Detachment Azov.
We wrote to the Recruiting Center that we
want to get to the unblocking of Mariupol.
We were told that we were active policemen
and the transfer was not possible.
Then, I wrote,
we will quit.
Will you take us as civilians?
I wrote.
Then he wrote from his phone.
For the third time, when we wrote there,
they already associated us, roughly speaking.
They write to him, you are probably friends.
This one and that one.
You are probably friends.
Fine.
You won't get to the unblocking.
But if you want to go to Azov, go and prove it at the BITC.
We got to the first BITC after a full-scale invasion.
Explain the BITC term to the viewers.
Basic Initial Training Course.
Endurance, physical abilities, stamina course.
It is difficult.
In means, they don't accept easily to Azov?
No.
It's not possible.
Which exams should you pass?
It used to be called Physical Education.
Yes.
There are Physical Education, and stress resistance, and
medicine, and fire training, you have to know everything.
Everyone is prepared for the hardest, for the infantry.
We were told in order to be an infantryman,
you need to be able to do everything,
you need to be physically hardy, morally
strong, able to make difficult decisions,
you need to develop critical thinking very much and then show
it in practice because you can't relax being an infantryman.
Everyone is preparing for infantry, and then someone
can, for example, become a machine gunner, am I right?
A machine gunner is also an infantryman.
Okay, and then which position can you take after an infantry?
Yes, then you can try in artillery or as a drone operator.
Now I don't know, I won't tell you exactly, but
when I went to Azov, the sergeant told me,
you have to serve in the infantry for a year, and only
then you can ask questions about transportation,
for example, in artillery, or somewhere else.
Like, you have to look at this war
with the eyes of an infantryman.
Have you ever regretted it?
No.
Well, I don't want to...
In general, I didn't care.
By the way, I was a senior lieutenant in the police,
and they told me during the interview in the recruiting center,
why?
Why are you doing this?
After the war, no one will tell you a word that you laid low.
You had your own job, you had your own business.
Well, I think that I would not have
done enough if I had been a policeman.
Well, this is only my choice, I
don't impose it on anyone, so to speak.
I became a soldier, that's it, I became a soldier.
That is, you are now a Private.
No.
We are already officers.
What rank?
I am a lieutenant.
I am a junior lieutenant.
You are a junior lieutenant.
That is, you catching up quickly.
I was just in the position of the chief sergeant of the platoon,
and then I was appointed commander of the platoon,
and I was in charge of the duties of the commander of the platoon.
Why do you constantly troll Spartan about his age?
No, I'm Spartan, it's Iraq.
Sorry, Iraq.
Because he loves me, I'm sure.
Well, I'm younger.
I have more ambitions.
I'm not younger, but I'm older.
But I'm older and wiser, right?
Yes, I think so.
So that he doesn't relax.
I see.
Now you are choosing personnel,
as far as I understand, right?
As far as it is possible to say, yes.
We have already been on interviews many times, and yes, yes.
Is it more difficult to be a Private
than to be a commander, or vice versa?
It's easier to be a private because, well,
let's say, you will be given instructions,
you have already had been thought about, but,
well, we are the same soldiers to our leadership.
We are also given instructions, we carry out orders.
Well, I would be much calmer if I were a simple soldier.
Well, because I am constantly worried
when they give us some tasks,
and in general, for the personnel, well, all
commanders are worried about personnel.
We just came from the same Basic Combat Training together.
The guys and I, together on this course pushed the
soil, then they put me as their commander,
and I'm like, damn it.
Well, after two years, there are such close
relations, and, well, this is already a family.
That is, the family that is at home is a
family, and here, here is your family.
And when you make a decision or give
them some task, then, I don't know,
you think five hundred times, everything is
like this, so that everything goes good there.
They tell me that Iraq and Spartan
are very effective commanders, right?
What is the efficiency of the Azov?
Well, first of all, for the Azovs, for any
military, the main goal is to perform a combat task
and to preserve the personnel.
You, before giving orders to the soldiers,
you have to understand that you give orders
not just to the soldiers, you give it to the life,
you give it to the life of their wives after this,
and you give it to the life of the parents
after your wrong order, well, incompetent.
You have to think five hundred times and make
a decision that will lead to effective performance
and preservation of your personnel.
Well, for me personally, this is priority number one.
So that the guys go and return alive, healthy, and well.
Because it is very difficult when there are losses in the unit.
Well, for me personally, it is very difficult
to meet with the parents, with the wives,
with the sisters of our guys who died there.
Well, to explain all this to them, they ask how it was, and why so.
Whether you like it or not, when you communicate like this, you ...
consider yourself to be guilty anyway.
Well, even though it may not...
It all may not depend on you.
...not depend on you, but I have such a constant feeling.
And when ... Well, this is my biggest fear.
When all these conversations, when it happens,
when it needs to be explained, to go to farewell, to look at it all,
when the parents ...
wife, parents are crying there, and you stand there and think,
damn, somewhere here it was my shortcoming.
Did I do everything to prevent it?
Even if you did everything, you still look for it.
Well, you know, I think it's better to be like that,
it's better to be worried about it than to just say,
go ahead, go ahead, pick a spot.
You have to think about it, you have to constantly consider it.
Because when you are with the guys, you are there, next to them,
when you see what they feel, what they see,
how it all goes around,
only after that you already understand
how to do it the right way, what is right.
Because you look not only from the command line,
but you also see with the eyes of a soldier how he will do it,
and in general, whether he will be able to do it.
Because for them, in our unit, especially for infantrymen,
we try to create the most comfortable
conditions during the combat mission
so that they come in and show their skills.
Three hours later.
Stabilization point
Greetings.
Natalia.
Drama. hello.
One minute, I`m eating vitamins.
Here we are with the shootings.
Greetings.
Did you recognize?
I saw you somewhere. There was a small screen, like this.
I don't remember where.
Hello, my friend.
What's your name?
Trauma.
That's it. Trauma.
Oleksandr.
Mr. Oleksandr. How long have
you been Trauma?
Since the beginning of the full-scale invasion.
I was in the territorial defense at first.
They were already giving out, well,
not giving out, but choosing nicknames.
Well, since I am an orthopedic traumatologist
according to my civil specialty,
it has clung this way.
Where did you work as a traumatologist?
In Kremenchuk.
How did you end up in Azov?
At first, I was in the 145th Battalion of the 116th Brigade.
This is the Poltava region.
I was near Bakhmut.
Then I was in Kurakhove, the last zone.
When I was still there, I applied through the recruitment center.
Here is such an ageism, look.
They push with their elbows and say, oh, you are already 36.
Already 36.
Yeah.
There is a biological age, and there is a psychological age.
I have a psychological age of 30-32.
Oh, I see.
Yes, you can show off, of course.
Well, that's the situation.
I see.
This is a dug-out in the ground.
Dug out.
It is calculated so that the distance to the largest
combat zone is three and a half kilometers.
Three and a half?
Three and a half kilometers.
We often hear the cannonade and the shootout.
There are strikes here sometimes.
So, if you stay a little longer, you can...
You can see the results, the ground
is shaking here.
Yes.
Listen, Mr. Oleksandr, you say that you are a traumatologist.
Well, I understand that an injury is not a fracture.
As a rule, if there is General Physical Training, and it is not my
first day in medicine, then I have already gone through a lot.
That is, working in district hospitals,
in city hospitals, so I already saw it.
Plus, working with other teams, for example, in
Kurakhove, there was a surgical transfer group...
a surgical group where surgeons worked, and
there was also an oncologist in that group,
who also worked as a surgeon, so we
know what to do in all surgical professions.
The question of experience and the question
of something else are separate issues.
And the guys with you, what do they do?
Anesthesiologist.
Anesthesiologist. What's your name?
My name is Mikhailo.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
And you have another assistant.
Felsher.
You are Felsher. What's your name?
Zhenya.
Mr. Yevhen, nice to meet you.
You haven't had any patients today, have you?
What do you mean? We already had five people.
You just missed each other.
Did you have any serious injuries today?
I wouldn't say serious, but problematic.
In any case, you need to control these things.
Now he is yellow, and on the road he can be black or red.
It's better to look closely, it's better to control.
Where did the guys go just now from you?
Slavyansk.
Please tell us about blood transfusion,
because it is talked about as a know-how which...
First of all, it is necessary.
Yes, which is simply necessary now.
Because blood flow is critical.
Before, blood transfusion was prohibited in the trenches.
Not that it was strictly prohibited, there was no resolution.
Resolution.
You need strong will everywhere, right?
Well, you have to be brave enough to do it.
Well, to do it.
Because now, I say it again, he can be yellow or half-red.
Blood loss.
While they're driving, we can lose a person.
One of the causes of death is blood loss.
You do blood transfusions, don't you?
It's better to ask an anesthesiologist.
Because I work with my hands.
Was there a blood transfusion today?
We haven't had it, but the transfusion
was done by our combat medics before our stage.
They have already poured a unit of blood.
That is, the patient came to us.
Right there, on the spot?
Yes.
It's critical.
You just have to do it all.
It's technically not difficult.
You have the right equipment.
Why be afraid?
There is a question...
No, just like that...
Some people are just afraid.
Even when I imagine, for example, in
a trench, on the ground, and a medic can do it?
A medic who is in a trench, has no blood with him, because he
needs to carry a refrigerator with him, and it is quite difficult.
He is both a combat unit and a combat medic.
Therefore, it is difficult to combine a combat backpack,
a medic's backpack, and a refrigerator.
But at a certain distance from the
front edge, that is, at a very short distance,
so that the soldier could be delivered there as quickly as
possible, there is already a certain place, a certain lodge,
where there are experienced combat medics who master
these methods, who are well-educated and well-educated.
They understand what they are doing when they
are doing it, and what they are doing it for.
They bring the wounded to this sorting point
where he is examined, given first aid,
and, in particular, if there is a need for
blood transfusion or plasma, it is carried out there.
Where are you from?
I am from Dnipro.
There I spent, probably ...
What hospital did work in?
In the regional children's hospital.
Really?
I am a children's doctor-anesthesiologist, yes.
The school of superheroes has opened there,
in the oncology department, maybe you know.
Yes, I know.
You can say hello to your colleagues, children.
Hello to everyone, children, I hope they
have all signed out, and all colleagues, hello.
This is an opportunity to thank them.
Yes.
Sometimes happens that, I'll say a little pessimistically,
as an orthopedic traumatologist, the boys are seeking help
with diseases of the musculoskeletal system from me.
In particular, the spine, in particular, the knee.
Well, wear combat gear, wear armor, wear a helmet.
Hernia, protrusions, meniscus.
When you are treating them, it gets better.
That is, the boys are satisfied, then they are brought here.
Sometimes they are dead.
They have become better, they are satisfied.
I already tell them what sanatorium they'll go to.
And then they are brought here dead.
It's a pity.
This situation.
The intensive care ward has absolutely everything at a minimum.
Here we have wrapped blankets for the patient.
So that it does not get wet.
So that it can be wiped.
And at the same time, the heater is turned on.
This warmth is very critically important for our patients.
Artificial lung ventilation device, patient monitor, aspirator.
Well, it is portable.
You can use a portable artificial lung
ventilation device as well as a stationary.
Plus there is an oxygen concentrator.
Here we have a system for heating blood.
This is what gives us the opportunity to infuse the blood quickly.
To conduct a transfusion.
That is, it will be the temperature of thirty-nine degrees.
Is it a picture?
In this navigation, we need to
evaluate whether there is internal bleeding.
This is intrapleural hemorrhage,
intra-abdominal hemorrhage.
Is there pneumothorax or not?
If there is, we need to be
able to address the issue.
We use an ultrasound machine.
That is, we have an intensive therapy room here.
It is called a transformer with extended authority.
Absolutely in full capacity.
Trained?
Trained, yes.
Did you help the enemies, save the enemies?
Let's not say 'saved,' but helped.
There were such cases.
Well, was one interesting patient.
Altai region. Prisoner. Were kept in prison for two murders.
I liked to talk to him.
You, banderivtsi are all killers here.
You all need to be...
Well, he talked this nonsense that is called propaganda.
Propaganda.
I don't know how people talk to them in chat roulette.
Well, they cannot set them right.
How long does the shift last?
Three days.
Three-day shift?
Then one or two days of sleep and the beginning of another shift.
I imagine when you go into civilian life you will say,
I was on the front line for three days and you will
be able to as a doctor. When you become a chief.
When you come home to civilian life, for example, to Kremenchuk, and there is all the light, people walk.
And you came from a place where
the light is not turned on at night.
At night, yes.
And there people walk with children.
There is a light.
A contrast.
I wish you not to have patients.
Thank you.
I wish you to have only the little ones.
I wish everything ends fine.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Yevhen.
Good luck.
Goodbye.
What did you come out here?
We would not like to interfere, Natalia.
Be careful.
No, no, I remember the order.
It's a checkpoint there.
I'm afraid to raise such a topic. I raise it, I ...
It always gives me a lot of trouble.
I asked both Zelensky and Budanov how to look into the
eyes of the parents when you give awards, for example.
Well, I see that everyone becomes
human when they answer this question.
Just people, without camouflage.
Yes.
They become naked people.
Because, you know, it's hard.
Hard, very hard.
It's hard because, you know, when we
lose our precious soldiers, it's eating me up inside.
I mean, why does it happen?
If these people have to build this country,
and these people are our nation?
Well, someone ...
I believe that the nation is those who do something for
their country so that we can win with any of our efforts.
Those who did not lift a finger are just people.
Just people.
I understand what you mean, yes.
When such a time passes ...
I also ask this question. What is the
difference between a nation and a people?
People, guys, they lose their health.
They are there ...
Someone can ...
Well, someone performs a combat mission, and he ...
He has injuries that prevent him from continuing to serve.
Someone died there.
You understand that there will hardly be such people anymore.
Unfortunately.
Because all those who ...
Who had such ambitions.
To dedicate oneself.
To dedicate oneself to the unit, to the nation.
Dedicate yourself completely to your brother-in-arms.
Now, unfortunately, they are already ...
They are not with us.
As we see, yes.
These people are not with us.
Well, there are already a lot of people like that
died, or they are, you know, physically limited.
New such warriors are not very eager to go.
What happened to your leg?
With mine?
Uh-huh.
Well, nothing. Just a
little ligament. That's all.
Really?
Yes.
Is he lying?
It is all true.
The war two years ago and the war now.
It's different.
The enemy is also making conclusions.
Trying to improve.
Not standing still.
Tell me... I'm sorry for the formulation, is there now
a tough technical war, without hatred towards them?
Well, like in the computer game?
Just killing or ...
I will speak for myself.
or do you hate them?
Well, hatred...
I just have to do it, and do it, and keep doing
it as long as I have enough strength and health.
I just do it.
Hate? Well, and there is hate, yes.
Why? I don't know...
My parents worked faithfully hard to
earn money, built a house, acquired something.
At any moment, a rocket can just fly into
my house, and that's it, it won't be there.
I have a father from the Donetsk region,
and my grandparents are buried there,
in the Donetsk region.
I can't just go to their cemetery,
because someone came to liberate that land.
I have enough motivation, and
it won't cease for a very long time.
There will be as much as it takes of it.
So, there is hatred?
Well, I had it at first, and now, it's not just work,
you just know that it's an enemy, that he
came, that he wants to do something with you.
If you don't kill him,
he will kill you.
And this enemy has been here for a long time, and
he just needs to be eliminated, and that's it.
Hatred, it's probably more
about civil people, because,
well, they view it in another way.
When you've been working...
The biggest motivation for me
at the moment,
obviously, is to return to our borders
and all that,
but I want revenge for the brother-in-arms, which
they killed because there won't be anyone like them.
Do they come to you?
They come.
Yes.
Even recently, yes.
Decent people come, we work with them, and then they fit in the
team, in the family, in the unit,
because you have not only to fit
in the unit by head, but also by heart.
It is necessary to become not a
person in Azov, but the Azovian himself,
There is a category, this is my...
Invention?
Subjective opinion,
there are people who do it for money,
some do it for something else,
and there are people who just come,
I really hope that we don't have such people,
but there are people who come
purely for commercial purposes.
In Azov?
Well, I don't think it is true for Azov, but in other units, yes.
I know this...
Do you condemn such people?
Well, yes.
Really?
I'm paid one hundred thousand hryvnias,
it doesn't matter if I die.'
Their motivation...
But they do the work.
Yes, they work, but their motivation is money.
How money can be a motivation when your country is being destroyed, civil people are dying, and children, and women?
What other motivation is there? Money?
What if to consider it compensation
for the fact that you are freezing, working, digging?
In general, it doesn't bother me.
I would agree to compensate my
parents for the fact that my mother does not see her son.
Let me eat, take a bath, and wash my clothes.
I don't need anything else.
Okay.
When I am a civilian, when the war
ends, then I will think about money,
how to build your civilian life further.
But where...
I mean, I understand it, but not really.
I will go away,
and I will still think about your words.
Look, everyone has their own story.
The money is important to someone.
Maybe, someone is serving and
building a house at the time, or investing.
I do not judge.
I'm telling the truth, it is my subjective opinion.
I think so.
I do not impose my opinion on anyone,
it's just my point of view.
I am cool this way.
Azov is such a unit, which
is shrouded in legends,
and the tragedy that happened in 2022.
There was a series of tragedies.
Their exit, despite the order to save lives, is also a tragedy.
Because later there were Olenivka and tortures.
Do guys that have been through it tell you something?
Do they talk sincerely? Are there moments of soldier truth?
Of course, there are.
We try not to ask about it.
We understand how it is there and what is going on there.
We try not to bother them with it so that they do not
return in their thoughts to what they went through there.
Personally, I understand what's going on there.
Everything is visible in their appearance
when they come out of captivity.
Personally, I'm not interested. I never asked about it.
If a person talks about it, just remembers the topic during
the conversation. 'We had it like that.' I would listen.
I never ask, why, how, tell me. It's unpleasant for me to hear.
I don't even talk about...
How they survived it.
Well, such fighters, such warriors,
can you recognise them among personnel?
Are clearly visible?
Yes.
Certainly, there are no others here.
Of course, I completed the last combat mission.
In general, I have a very young platoon.
All the guys are born starting from 2000.
There are from 2002, 2003, 2004, even 2005.
Wow.
Yes, and I just set a task for a person, and as much as I
am a psychologist, I immediately scan the reception.
I don't see any doubts in their eyes.
Or any pause, or that he is doubting something.
A person completes the task.
How did you earn this trust?
Well, probably with the same system,
that I have never let them down.
Do you have to be completely honest with your subordinates?
Never.
You can't.
Once you slip up, and that's it.
There will be no trust.
You will not have that authority.
You should say directly what awaits them?
To say what awaits them as much as it is necessary
for them, as much as they are ready to accept it.
This is such a balance, you know.
This must be understood.
One needs to be given full information, one needs
only a part, and another needs to be given nothing.
It's like, you know, being a conductor.
A creative person to command.
Because each person has a personality.
And someone needs a kick, and someone just needs a conversation.
You will know how to approach them only when you
are constantly on the same wavelength with them.
And you will understand who is who.
You need to live the lives of your fighters.
I'll tell you that when I think about how you can ask,
force, demand from a person to leave the Azovstal
when the person is in a complete block and surrounded.
The human brain understands that you are going to meet death.
How can you give such an order as a commander?
How can you convince a person to go and do it?
Look, here ...
How did they do it?
They did it, I think, based on their full trust in their commander.
Yes, it is true.
They, in the first place, for their commander, can go to the end
and perform the most difficult task in general.
We trust our commander.
They give us tasks, and we perform them.
This is, perhaps, one of the few links
that distinguish us from other units and in general in the world.
Because we completely trust our commander.
Completely.
And all our guys.
The commander has a great deal of authority.
With all these years, when the war is still going on, it is only growing.
I will say one thing.
The commander of the company, the commander of
the battalion, the commander of the brigade.
These are, I think, the most competent people,
the most authoritative people for me.
I don't need anything else.
Well, it's worth serving with people like that.
Yes, that's all.
Even, you know ...
Under their leadership.
Our company commander.
We communicate with him long enough, for me it`s clearly to
understand when he is my friend and when he is my leader.
I don't need to be reminded of it many times.
How not to cross the line?
Well, at work, when there is work, we ...
I know when he is my friend,
I know when he is my commander.
We work as commanders and subordinates.
Sometimes we can come to talk to him,
go somewhere, drink coffee, have a snack.
Yes.
I talk to him frankly quite often.
I stay with him, and we already have a
dialogue as two friends.
And I told him frankly that, even though...
by the way, a company commander is a few years younger than me,
I told him, even though he is younger than
me, I consider him my older brother.
Well, I have respect for this person.
And only in Azov, you can just
go to your company commander, talk to him,
Soul to soul.
Only in Azov, the commander of the
battalion can tell you, Iraq, let's go eating.
Just like that.
Redis, tell me, what kind of person is he?
A standard.
What is the distance between you and him?
Look, we don't see him very often,
because we have expanded into the brigade,
and he has a lot of his own work.
When we were preparing for the task,
we worked on the tactical maneuvers,
and he was present,
we communicated with him, he
was completely ... In the process.
He was involved in our work,
he was interested ...
You can make a comparison.
You had a leader, well, with all respect
to your former leadership in the police.
No, these were not leaders.
These were not leaders.
Really?
Really.
These are not leaders.
Not commanders,
these are not leaders.
Here you see and understand
that this is a commander.
What is his strength?
He is a commander.
He is simple, I don't know how to
say it correctly, he has humanity, so to speak.
The compliance of his position.
Yes.
He is a professional.
You communicate with him,
you talk to him, he is constantly ...
What is a professional?
In Azovstal, he went out in combat fights, right?
Now he is a commander, right?
He is a commander,
but he goes to the front line,
he comes to our positions,
he comes to our command point.
Directly to the front line.
How does he make people comply?
How does it happen?
How is this magic, when you understand that this
person is an authority, an undisputed authority?
He has such energy, I don't know how to explain it.
His energy works with the subconsciousness.
Yes, the subconsciousness.
He works with trust.
It is easy to talk to him.
He addresses work issues clearly. Once we talked and
he asked, why do you want to do this way?
And you tell him ...
Do you communicate formally?
No, he communicates informally with us.
Calls us by our nicknames or 'friends'.
Yes, asks, why is it so?
And I explain to him, for example, well, here we
decided this way, because... and I am giving arguments.
He listens.
Or gives some order.
He can also advise something.
Then he says,
Iraq,
I want to see this.
Well, I have my own conclusions,
I announce them to the personnel,
and we do it.
The commander then approves,
yes or no.
Are commanders involved in personal matters?
Well, not to say that they are involved.
Well, if they are military matters or just...?
No, your personal matters.
No.
Well, he can ask what's up.
Well, if you initiate a personal conversation,
and you may need advice or help,
then you will be listened to,
and there will be as much as possible help and effort for you.
Who finds out that the fighter is burning out?
Who finds out that the fighter is on the edge?
Who finds out that the fighter needs psychological help?
Brother-in-arms and the commander,
this is a common issue.
Do you have some kind of warning?
Yes,
When you have to report about it.
The guys come up and say, friend,
the commander, pay attention to this and that.
I literally sit down,
and I understand what he needs.
One needs just a
conversation, as I said before,
one just needs to miss the combat mission.
Well, everyone carries the load in their own way.
Just give them a rest.
That's it, the next time he goes to the
battle recovered, worked with himself, he's ready.
I personally had a case when a fighter came up to
me and said that it was morally difficult for him.
He needed to rest because he...
Do you ask about the reasons?
Well, I understand, he's a combat doctor,
a very good one who saved a lot of lives.
He's a robot.
Who are you talking about?
This is a platoon doctor, Circus, friend, a fighter of the 2nd platoon.
He did a lot on this mission,
a lot of successful evacuations.
He also has the same attitude towards his brother-in-arms,
like, we are from the same course,
and it's very difficult for him, when
they get wounded, when they feel bad,
when he needs to work,
he doesn't like it very much,
he says, when I need to
work, I don't like it very much,
because everything is fine
when he doesn't work,
but when he works,
he helps someone,
it's hard for him,
he carries everything in himself,
he is also a professional in his field,
and then, if something goes wrong, he sits for hours and think
whether he did the right thing,
although he is, a professional, and I trust
him, as well as the commander of the company,
everyone in our company knows what he can do.
As the commander of another platoon, I also trust him
We train young people who come to
us, that, in our company, we don't have,
the second platoon, the
third platoon, the first platoon,
Yes, it exists legally,
we have the first platoon.
For my personnel, my friend Spartan, it's an authority.
We train every soldier that we are one platoon, and if there are difficulties
or problems in the second platoon, it can`t be not interesting for the third platoon,
We do the same work, protect the same country.
The last combat mission we
had, we did with two platoons, together
and the guys,
communicated and interacted well with each other.
Guys, at the age of 18, under shelling, under
enemy grenade drop carried food and water for the guys,
clearly understanding that because of this
bottle of water, this distance, he can not return.
Why do they go to you at the age of 18?
Why do they go?
Because they are carrying, that's it.
That's it.
They do not need to look for additional motivation.
They are the cream of the nation, as
they say, these 18-year-olds and 19-year-olds.
Who protect their country.
To be honest, I do not communicate
with anyone, except for Spartan,
and that's it.
I do not know what it was before.
You know, with the beginning of
all this that happened to our country.
Everything fell into place, everyone
showed their true colors.
I'm tired of watching Instagram
stories of people who used to surround me,
who I still follow,
who don't know what to do with themselves.
Theater, hookah, park.
Theater, karaoke.
People have so much free time that
they don't know how to deal with it.
When I come home and my blood pressure is 160
and I don't know which pill to take,
I normalize blood pressure with one medicine,
but my headache doesn't go away.
And so on.
He is 34.
My mom texts me,
asking when she will see me.
At least for a day.
Someone else goes to karaoke.
And a beach.
Yes.
Soon there will be one.
Soon there will be a beach.
In these months.
I can ask about these red threads,
but there will be no answer.
I can answer.
I also can.
Really?
It's easier for him.
He knows more about it.
My mom put it on me and said to wear it.
Really?
Yes.
So there is someone more important than Redis.
I am a faithful man.
That's it.
Then again, I don't impose it upon anyone.
I have my attitude
and treat it my own way.
That's it.
Listen, guys, does ideology weigh a lot in Azov?
Yes.
Did you accept it before you were tested?
Probably yes.
You do not accept it,
it comes to you on its own, subconsciously.
Yes.
It's stupid to impose it.
How can you force to love your country, your nation?
You won't say,
that you have to do it.
To be a patriot.
To speak from a script like the Russians.
You know, they have scripts.
We don't do it.
When it comes to you,
you go to Azov.
That's how I think.
Without it, you can't come here, get here,
go through the course, get all these loads.
You understand why you are here.
It helps you morally and psychologically.
You have a fighting spirit all the time
because you know why you are here,
what you will do, and why you are doing it.
An attitude towards Azov.
Do you feel it?
Are there people who look at your chevron from the bottom up?
Well, they look in different ways.
They look in different ways.
I don't know who looks at me
from the bottom up or from the negative side.
Certainly, the looks aren't indifferent.
Well, in Kyiv, they look at me normally.
Here, when I come home to my relatives, it's fifty-fifty.
Really?
Well, yes.
We were in Kyiv sometime ago with Spartan
and with two of our brother-in-arms.
I don't even remember why.
We were exempt for two days.
We were going by the subway.
We were wearing T-shirts.
At that time, SPSD Azov had a T-shirt.
It was given to you?
Women and girls came up to us.
They just said, thank you.
It was uncomfortable.
Very uncomfortable, honestly.
The guys didn't do anything.
It's harder for the guys.
Grandmothers and grandfathers are sitting on the benches.
You pass by, they look at you like this.
They think, are you a fascist?
Really?
Yes.
Well, you see how people look at you.
Someone looks at you normally.
Someone respects you.
Someone thinks that you are a punisher of Russian children.
And that's it.
If not an Azov officer, but an officer from the Armed Forces of Ukraine.
Do they look at you differently?
I think they look at everyone the same way,
but the Azov officer is just special.
So, they are good boots as they said that
in Soviet film comedy, you have to take them.
Yes.
Then again, Russian script works well for those who watch it.
It's all those old people who watch these...
Well, not only old people.
There are also adults, basically people who ...
You are looking at him and he has his own cinema there.
He watched a lot of Pervyi Channel.
Well, when we were going here,
we saw a satellite that is on every house.
They used to be set up for Moscow.
I don't know what they are watching.
I think they watch the same thing.
Did we do something to cut the signal? It is possible to do?
To be honest, I don't know, but if I had any
direct relation to this, I would do it in the first place.
If people are still watching in 2024,
and everything is not that simple.
They have problems with their heads.
They shouldn't live here, at least.
I'm not saying that they should be killed, they just need to be
put on a train or bus and let them go there, beyond the curb.
That's it.
We want to build our country, so that
everyone is a patriot, so that everyone loves it.
And we want to bring back the Ukrainian spirit.
Everyone wears Vyshyvanka.
This is my favorite topic.
Everyone loves it terribly, you know.
Yes, they love it terribly.
They love it terribly at their homes.
Language, faith, church, and you know, everyone is kissing,
and as a result, we have corrupt people in Vyshyvankas.
Yes, it is so.
I forgot to ask,
you said that you wanted to go to the unblocking, right?
When the guys came out and you looked
at these shots, what did you think?
What were your feelings then?
Well, it hurt a lot.
It must have been a feeling of compassion.
I understood why it happened. Because it was necessary
to help the heavily wounded or they would have just died.
They would've died.
Everyone understood.
It was just hard to understand.
Even, well, I think that even civilians
understand that our enemy cannot be trusted.
The pre-agreements according to which they came out,
were not, unfortunately, fulfilled by them.
No third party would lift a finger.
I was 90% sure that it was for washing the eyes, to show, from their side,
that they still have some kind of military honor, some military rules of war.
In fact, we have seen, we see it to this day,
how they behave and what they do there.
That's why further negotiations, it's a joke.
So how will this war end?
I think it will end sooner or later with our victory,
but it should end on their territory.
When our army will be there.
When we can impose on them our conditions, then we will win.
This is, well, like, this is my subjective opinion.
Well, there is war mathematics.
There are fewer of us.
Yes, there are fewer of us.
So, in this decision, something needs to be corrected.
Well, if...
There hasn't been such a turning point yet.
It hasn't happened yet.
It will happen someday.
It will happen, no matter how many there are of us and them.
According to the number of the army.
When this moment comes, it will stop working.
Already during the full-scale war, I think that our army has already proven
this many times and shown that the number does not always matter.
If we use our strength correctly and effectively, use the weapons
that we are given, I hope that they keep giving it to us, help us,
and not hold us on this leash, and our unit in general, which
is not provided with Western weapons and equipment at all.
And then, if we do all this...
Do you not have Western or American weapons?
We have ...
Or is this war secret?
Okay, that's it.
We may already have it, but only from the state.
Not from the state?
Yes.
Well, from volunteers and good people.
Although, our higher management has already asked,
what else we have to do to be given it.
What else to prove?
I want to say to the viewers that we will also have a fundraising.
This fundraising will be for the Azov brigade.
The only thing is that now I can't say whether it
will be for medical needs or for military needs.
Because I will talk to your management
and we will already decide with them.
It was said by the youth about the picture of the end of the war.
And now wisdom will speak.
Yes.
What?
Ask.
What do you see as the end of the war?
Of course, our victory.
We will do everything for this.
Everything.
Beginning with a soldier to an officer.
And we are doing everything for this
and we keep doing.
As I said earlier.
As long as we have enough strength
we will not give up.
Honestly, sometimes I get tired, let's say, morally.
But I tell you, I have enough motivation for a long time.
When will you cut your hair, Iraq?
I will cut my hair after we are withdrawn from this direction.
Then I will cut my hair.
This is some kind of ...
Well, my superstitions.
During some period I determined for myself, I do not cut my hair.
Well, I hope that you will soon see a friend with a haircut.
He has already cut himself.
He already sends me photos and says, this is how I want it.
So that you cut your hair.
Yes, yes.
So that he looked like a human.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for this conversation.
Thank you for the interview.
Thank you.
I just came.
Hello. My name is Ilya.
Brigade Azov. National Guard of Ukraine.
Oh, Azov. Cool. Let's work.
Okay, good.
By the way, we are not Nazis.
Oh. Yes. I understood. Yes.
Well, society expects that the next day,
after the end of the war, there will be elections.
Therefore, all the soldiers whom they love, value,
and who they`re grateful to, will come to the Verkhovna Rada.
Expecting.
They want.
Not just the Verkhovna Rada.
Then again, there are wishes and there are reality.
Are they wanting you in the politics?
Well, yes.
Those people who bribe very often act like a puppeteer.
Well yes.
I do not like such people and I am very suspicious of them.
Does the front line now look like it is in a positional impasse?
No, the front line is moving, everywhere, Russians are pushing.